Austin Derbique

Software Engineer

O Tempe, AZ, 85281

in www.linkedin.com/in/aderbique

austin@derbique.us www.derbique.org

Forward-thinking Software Engineer with 5 years of professional experience architecting, designing, and writing code for highly scalable, complex workloads. Excellent tolerance for ambiguity and collaboration with peers. Diverse background in Cloud, Embedded, and Autonomous Systems. Foundational knowledge with undergraduate and graduate degrees in Computer Science making for a well rounded approach to software development & project management.



Skills

Cloud Architecture

Security & Compliance

Backend Development

Communication with Peers

Tolerance for Ambiguity

Excellent Very Good

Very Good

Excellent

••••• Excellent



Work History

Software Engineer, VICE

Viasat, Tempe, AZ

- Working to build out a global identity system scaling to thousands of users across multiple partner companies in AWS without using VPCs.
- Additionally responsible for developing & maintaining Viasat Cloud Engineering products (VICE). This includes highly available (HA) infrastructure for a variety of systems such as LDAP, JWT, SAML, OIDC, PKI, and DNS services.
- Additional responsibilities include On-Call rotational shifts to support internal customers for mission critical workloads servicing commercial airlines, aovernment, and residential subscribers.
- Reduced organization cloud cost usage by tens of thousands of dollars

Software Engineer, Operations

Viasat, San Diego, CA

 Architected, implemented, & deployed HA, NIST 800-171 compliant workloads in multi cloud environments.

2021-03 - Current

2018-02 - 2021-03

2017-05 - 2017-08

2016-01 - 2016-12

2015-06 - 2015-08

2020-08 - 2022-04

2013-08 - 20172

- Led multiple migration efforts for workloads from on-premise to AWS & OpenStack.
- Performed as subject matter expert for AWS and offered cloud consulting to neighboring teams.
- Served as Tech Lead for new products and maintained direct involvement from project inception to completion.

Embedded Test Development Intern, Operations

Viasat, San Diego, CA

- Performed embedded kernel development on FPGAs as well as build out automation and test procedures using Yocto & Python.
- Decreased build time by 70% by intelligently building for specified targets.

Design Engineering Intern

Samsung Electronics, Logan, Utah

- Performed firmware & hardware prototype testing.
- Created & updated PCB designs & layouts for visual displays.
- Responsible for BOM management of visual displays for Samsung ERP systems.

Radio Frequency Engineering Intern

Infineon Technologies, Munich, Germany

- Performed radio frequency measurements (S-Parameter, Harmonics).
- Assembled & verified evaluation boards.
- Wrote automation of measurement processes in Matlab to better visualize performance of chips. Reduced report generation time by 90%.
- Played key-role in adopting new automation methods for parameter verification.



Education

Master of Science: Computer Science

Arizona State University - Tempe, AZ

- Research Interests include Edge Computing, IoT, Autonomous Vehicles, Software Defined Networks, Adversarial attacks on CPS
- Dean's List Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Fall 2021
- Current Graduate GPA of 3.8
- Team member of Virtualized Infrastructures, Systems, and Applications (VISA) Lab at ASU.

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Utah State University - Logan, UT

- Minored in Mathematics, Physics
- Dean's List Spring 2017
- Graduated with 3.45 GPA
- President of Free Software & Linux Club (FSLC)
- Member of Autonomous Robotics Submarine Team (RoboSub)



Certifications



Methodologies

- Object Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Don't Repeat Yourself (DRY)
- Scrum / Agile / Kanban
- DevOps
- Objectives and Key Results (OKRs)



Software

AWS, OpenStack, GCP

Linux (RHEL, Debian Systems), Windows

Version Control Management (Git)

Atlassian Products (Jira, Confluence)

CI/CD (Gitlab, Jenkins)

Monitoring (Grafana, Cloudwatch, PagerDuty)

Excellent Very Good

Languages

• Python, Bash, Java

NodeJS, Matlab, MIPS Assembly

Haskell, Prolog, Verilog, C++

Excellent

Very Good

Excellent

Excellent

Excellent

Very Good

Good



Interests

- Contributing to opensource projects. See https://comma.ai
- Learning new programming languages & methodologies
- Writing literature surveys on emerging computer science fields. See LinkedIn for posts